<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Homebrew</name>
		<description>The Dwarf race from My Personal homebrew shit 🏠🍲</description>
		<author url="https://github.com/SirTalpaDeRedstoneville5885">SirTalpaDeRedstoneville5885</author>
		<update version="0.0.3">
			<file name="Dwarf_race.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/SirTalpaDeRedstoneville5885/Aurora_Personal/main/Razze/Dwarf_race.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>

	<element name="Dwarf 🏠🍲" type="Race" source="My Personal homebrew shit 🏠🍲" id="ID_HB_RACE_DWARF">
		<description>
			<p class="flavor">Kingdoms rich in ancient grandeur, halls carved into the roots of mountains, the echoing of picks and hammers in deep mines and blazing forges, a commitment to clan and tradition, and a burning hatred of goblins and orcs—these common threads unite all dwarves.</p>
			<h4>SHORT AND STOUT</h4>
			<p>Bold and hardy, dwarves are known as skilled warriors, miners, and workers of stone and metal. Though they stand well under 5 feet tall, dwarves are so broad and compact that they can weigh as much as a human standing nearly two feet taller. Their courage and endurance are also easily a match for any of the larger folk.</p>
			<p class="indent">Dwarven skin ranges from deep brown to a paler hue tinged with red, but the most common shades are light brown or deep tan, like certain tones of earth. Their hair, worn long but in simple styles, is usually black, gray, or brown, though paler dwarves often have red hair. Male dwarves value their beards highly and groom them carefully.</p>
			<h4>LONG MEMORY, LONG GRUDGES</h4>
			<p>Dwarves can live to be more than 400 years old, so the oldest living dwarves often remember a very different world. For example, some of the oldest dwarves living in Citadel Felbarr (in the world of the Forgotten Realms) can recall the day, more than three centuries ago, when orcs conquered the fortress and drove them into an exile that lasted over 250 years. This longevity grants them a perspective on the world that shorter-lived races such as humans and halflings lack.</p>
			<p class="indent">Dwarves are solid and enduring like the mountains they love, weathering the passage of centuries with stoic endurance and little change. They respect the traditions of their clans, tracing their ancestry back to the founding of their most ancient strongholds in the youth of the world, and don't abandon those traditions lightly. Part of those traditions is devotion to the gods of the dwarves, who uphold the dwarven ideals of industrious labor, skill in battle, and devotion to the forge.</p>
			<p class="indent">Individual dwarves are determined and loyal, true to their word and decisive in action, sometimes to the point of stubbornness. Many dwarves have a strong sense of justice, and they are slow to forget wrongs they have suffered. A wrong done to one dwarf is a wrong done to the dwarf’s entire clan, so what begins as one dwarf’s hunt for vengeance can become a full-blown clan feud.</p>
			<h4>DWARF NAMES</h4>
			<ul class="unstyled">
				<li><strong>Male Names:</strong> Thargrim, Gorhulur, Brodur, Kazmak, Durnek, Vogruk, Tholmak, Grimhul, Rorkal, Kordrum, Atur, Aslan, Foghulur</li>
				<li><strong>Female Names:</strong> Tharnila, Dorgura, Foglurith, Kazrida, Vorlina, Zurneth, Tholgrida, Morrika, Bryndur, Glimara</li>
				<li><strong>Neutral Names:</strong> Drunvak, Kazril, Gorikaal, Rutharn, Vogrim, Torlen</li>
			</ul>
			<h4>DWARF TRAITS</h4>
			<p>Your dwarf character has an assortment of inborn abilities, part and parcel of dwarven nature.</p>			
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Ability Score Increase.</em></strong> Your Constitution score increases by 2.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Age.</em></strong> Dwarves mature at the same rate as humans, but they’re considered young until they reach the age of 75. On average, they live about 315 years.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Size.</em></strong> Dwarves stand between 4 and 5"6 feet tall and average about 150 pounds. Your size is Medium.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Speed.</em></strong> Your base walking speed is 30 feet.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Natural Armor. </i></b> Due to your hard skin and the shape of your body, you are ill-suited to wearing armor. Your skin provides ample protection, however; it gives you a base AC of 17 (your Dexterity modifier doesn't affect this number). You gain no benefit from wearing armor, but if you are using a shield, you can apply the shield's bonus as normal.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Darkvision.</em></strong> Accustomed to life underground, you have superior vision in dark and dim conditions. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can’t discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Tool Proficiency.</em></strong> You gain proficiency with the artisan’s tools of your choice: smith’s tools, jeweler's tools, or mason’s tools.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Languages.</em></strong> You can speak, read, and write Common and Dwarvish. Dwarvish is full of hard consonants and guttural sounds, and those characteristics spill over into whatever other language a dwarf might speak.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Subrace.</em></strong> There exist a rare mutation in dwarves, that makes them Arcane Dwarves.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<setters>
			<set name="names" type="male"> Thargrim, Gorhulur, Brodur, Kazmak, Durnek, Vogruk, Tholmak, Grimhul, Rorkal, Kordrum, Atur, Aslan, Foghulur</set>
			<set name="names" type="female"> Tharnila, Dorgura, Foglurith, Kazrida, Vorlina, Zurneth, Tholgrida, Morrika, Bryndur, Glimara</set>
			<set name="names" type="neutral"> Drunvak, Kazril, Gorikaal, Rutharn, Vogrim, Torlen</set>
			<set name="names" type="clan"> Clangemma, Fauci di Ferro, Martellorosso, Cuorescaglia, Scolpitoroccia, Spira d’Ossidiana, Zoccoli di Torma, Rompipietra, Rocciastridente, Forgiaombra</set>
			<set name="names-format">{{name}} {{clan}}</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>            
			<stat name="strength" value="1" />
          		<stat name="constitution" value="2" />
			<stat name="intelligence" value="1" />
			<stat name="innate speed" value="30" bonus="base" />
			<grant type="Size" id="ID_SIZE_MEDIUM" />
			<grant type="Vision" id="ID_VISION_DARKVISION" />
			<grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_COMMON" />
			<grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_DWARVISH" />
			<select type="Language" name="Customized Language" supports="Custom Race Language" number="2"  requirements="ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_LANGUAGE" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_HB_DWARVEN_NATURAL_ARMOR" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_HB_RACIAL_TRAIT_DWARVEN_TOOL_PROFICIENCY" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_DWARVEN_SUBRACE" />
		</rules>
	</element>
    <element name="Natural Armor" type="Racial Trait" source="My Personal homebrew shit 🏠🍲" id="ID_HB_DWARVEN_NATURAL_ARMOR">
        <description>
            <p>Due to your hard skin and the shape of your body, you are ill-suited to wearing armor. Your skin provides ample protection, however; it gives you a base AC of 17 (your Dexterity modifier doesn't affect this number). You gain no benefit from wearing armor, but if you are using a shield, you can apply the shield's bonus as normal.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Due to your hard skin and the shape of your body, you are ill-suited to wearing armor. Your skin provides ample protection, however; it gives you a base AC of 17 (your Dexterity modifier doesn't affect this number). You gain no benefit from wearing armor, but if you are using a shield, you can apply the shield's bonus as normal.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
			<stat name="Dwarf:natural armor" value="17" bonus="base" />
            <stat name="ac:calculation" value="Dwarf:natural armor" bonus="calculation" alt="Natural Armor (Dwarf)" />
        </rules>
    </element>
	<element name="Tool Proficiency" type="Racial Trait" source="My Personal homebrew shit 🏠🍲" id="ID_HB_RACIAL_TRAIT_DWARVEN_TOOL_PROFICIENCY">
		<description>
			<p>You gain proficiency with the artisan’s tools of your choice: smith’s tools, jeweler’s supplies, or mason’s tools.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false"/>
		<rules>
			<select type="Proficiency" name="Dwarven Tool Proficiency" supports="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_SMITHS_TOOLS|ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_BREWERS_SUPPLIES|ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_MASONS_TOOLS" />
			<select type="Proficiency" name="Simple Weapon or Tool, Dwarven Tool Proficiency" supports="Simple||Tool" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Dwarven Subrace" type="Racial Trait" source="My Personal homebrew shit 🏠🍲" id="ID_HB_RACIAL_TRAIT_DWARVEN_SUBRACE">
		<description>
			<p>There exist a rare mutation in dwarves, that makes them Arcane Dwarves.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false"/>
		<rules>
			<select type="Sub Race" name="Dwarven Subrace" supports="Dwarf 🏠🍲" />
		</rules>
	</element>
<!--Per qualche ragione lui funziona perfettamente-->
	<element name="Arcane Dwarf" type="Sub Race" source="My Personal homebrew shit 🏠🍲" id="ID_HB_SUB_RACE_ARCANE_DWARF">
		<supports>Dwarf 🏠🍲</supports>
		<description>
			<p>As an Arcane dwarf, you're strong and hardy, accustomed to a difficult life in rugged terrain. You’re way taller than any other dwarf, and have an extra pair of bulkier, stronger limbs.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Ability Score Increase.</em></strong> Your Strength score increases by 2.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Secondary arms.</em></strong> You have two slightly smaller secondary arms below your primary pair of arms. The secondary arms function like your primary arms, with the following exceptions: You can use a secondary arm to wield a weapon that has the light property, but you can’t use a secondary arm to wield other kinds of weapons.   You can’t wield a shield with a secondary arm..</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false"/>
		<setters>
			<set name="height" modifier="2d4">4'</set>
			<set name="weight" modifier="2d6">130 lb.</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="strength" value="1" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_HB_RACIAL_TRAIT_SECONDARY_ARMS" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Secondary arms" type="Racial Trait" source="My Personal homebrew shit 🏠🍲" id="ID_HB_RACIAL_TRAIT_SECONDARY_ARMS">
		<description>
			<p>You have two slightly smaller secondary arms below your primary pair of arms. The secondary arms function like your primary arms, with the following exceptions: You can use a secondary arm to wield a weapon that has the light property, but you can’t use a secondary arm to wield other kinds of weapons.   You can’t wield a shield with a secondary arm..</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="true">
			<description>You have two slightly smaller secondary arms below your primary pair of arms. The secondary arms function like your primary arms, with the following exceptions: You can use a secondary arm to wield a weapon that has the light property, but you can’t use a secondary arm to wield other kinds of weapons.   You can’t wield a shield with a secondary arm..</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
</elements>
